<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Path of the Cyborg</name>
		<update version="0.0.5">
			<file name="pathofthecyborg.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/KRANK3D/CustomContent/master/user-KRANK3D/pathofthecyborg.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Path of the Cyborg" type="Archetype" source="me" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG">
		<supports>Primal Path</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Barbarians who follow the Path of the Cyborg learn how to augment their rage abilities with the power stored inside Velin crystals. Electricity surges through their veins and their fury not only enhances their physical strength but grants them defenses as impermeable as the stone that gives them their power.  </p>
			<p class="indent"></p>
			<div element="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_SUDDEN_SHOCK" />
			<div element="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_SPIRIT_SHIELD" />
			<div element="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_CONSULT_THE_SPIRITS" />
			<div element="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_VENGEFUL_ANCESTORS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="true">
			<description>Some barbarians augment themselves with the power of Velin.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_SUDDEN_SHOCK" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_SPIRIT_SHIELD" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_CONSULT_THE_SPIRITS" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_VENGEFUL_ANCESTORS" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sudden Shock" type="Archetype Feature" source="me" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_SUDDEN_SHOCK">
		<description>
			<p>Starting when you choose this path at third level, you can channel electrical power into your weapon strikes. While you’re raging, the first creature you hit on each of your turns with a weapon attack takes extra lightning damage equal to 1d6 + half your barbarian level. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While you’re raging, the first creature you hit on each of your turns with a weapon attack takes extra lightning damage equal to 1d6 + half your barbarian level.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Spirit Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="me" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_SPIRIT_SHIELD">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 6th level, the guardian spirits that aid you can provide supernatural protection to those you defend. If you are raging and another creature you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by 2d6. When you reach certain levels in this class. you can reduce the damage by more: by 3d6 at 10th level and by 4d6 at 14th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When raging, if another creature within 30ft takes damage, you can reduce that damage by 2d6.</description>
			<description level="10">When raging, if another creature within 30ft takes damage, you can reduce that damage by 3d6.</description>
			<description level="14">When raging, if another creature within 30ft takes damage, you can reduce that damage by 4d6.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Consult the Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="me" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_CONSULT_THE_SPIRITS">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, you gain the ability to consult with your ancestral spirits. When you do so, you cast the augury or clairvoyance spell, without using a spell slot or material components. Rather than creating a spherical sensor, this use of clairvoyance invisibly summons one of your ancestral spirits to the chosen location. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells. After you cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>You can cast Augury or Clairvoyance without using a spell slot or material components and Wisdom as your spellcasting ability. Rather than creating a spherical sensor, this use of clairvoyance invisibly summons one of your ancestral spirits to the chosen location.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Vengeful Ancestors" type="Archetype Feature" source="me" id="ID_PATH_OF_THE_CYBORG_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_VENGEFUL_ANCESTORS">
		<description>
			<p>At 14th level, your ancestral spirits grow powerful enough to retaliate. When you use your Spirit Shield to reduce the damage of an attack, the attacker takes an amount of force damage equal to the damage that your Spirit Shield prevents.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use your Spirit Shield to reduce the damage of an attack, the attacker takes an amount of force damage equal to the damage that your Spirit Shield prevents.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
